(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.2",
"generated_at": "2026-06-27T00:44:15.724001",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
唸るぜ
I'll roar!
血泥 ついたて 守りたい
Covered in blood and mud, I want to protect this barrier.
革命道中だって
Even on this revolutionary journey,
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you.
暗闇 染み込む世界で
In a world soaked in darkness,
見つけた
I found...
センチメンタルな恋
...a sentimental love.
甘くのたうんだ眼差し
A sweet, twisting gaze,
変に色気あるから困った
you're strangely sexy, it's troubling.
手を繋ぐ勇気出したくて
I want to summon the courage to hold your hand,
身の程わきまえてちゃできないね
but I can't do it if I keep knowing my place.
暗いトンネルの壁
On the dark tunnel walls,
滴り落ちる秘密
dripping secrets...
しなやかに
...so gracefully.
なる心
...my heart throbs
ダメダメ！ 待て待て！
No, no! Wait, wait!
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even curses and illnesses
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
あぁ 唸るぜ
Ah, I'll roar!
嫉妬心ついたって 守りたい
Even with a jealous heart, I want to protect you
革命道中 だって君に夢中
On our journey of revolution, because I'm crazy about you
暗闇 染み込む 世界で
In a world soaked in darkness
見つけた
I found you
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
なりふり構わず 側にいたい
I want to be by your side, no matter how it looks
無器用な君にも 期待しちゃうよ
I'm starting to expect things, even from an awkward you
しがみつけば消えそうな灯に
On a light that seems like it would go out if held on to
爪を立てて 近づいて
Claw my way closer to you
身を任せるからさ 全て失ってもいい
Because I'll entrust myself to you, even if I lose everything
しなやかに高鳴る心
A gracefully throbbing heart
ダメダメ！ 待て待て！
No, no! Wait, wait!
呪いも病も君となら
With you, even curses and illnesses...
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
あぁ 泣けるぜ
Ah, it makes me weep!
絶句しちゃうまで 離れない
I won't leave you until I'm left speechless
革命道中 だって君に夢中
On our journey of revolution, because I'm crazy about you
旅の狭間で 見つけた
Found in the gaps of our journey,
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
突き進むなら 二人で
If we are to push forward, let's do it together
革命道中 だって夢に熱中
On our journey of revolution, because we're obsessed with our dream
ダメダメ！ 待て待て！
No, no! Wait, wait!
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even curses and illnesses
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
怖くたって 唸るぜ
Even if it's scary, I'll roar
嫉統心ついたって 守りたい
Even with a jealous heart, I want to protect you
革命道中 だって君に夢中
On our journey of revolution, because I'm crazy about you
暗闇 染み込む 世界で 見つけた
Found in a world soaked in darkness
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
いくぞー！
Here we go!
はい！ はい！ はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
そっと吐き出すため息を吸い込んだ
Taking a deep breath to quietly exhale,
後悔は苦い味残して
leaving a bitter taste of regret behind
いつもなんで？ 肝心なこと言えないまま
Always wondering why, unable to express my feelings,
次の朝日が顔だしてる
the next morning shows up
嫌になった運命をナイフで切り刻んで
I got tired of fate, cutting it into pieces with a knife
もう一度やり直したら
If I start over,
キキミに出会えないかも
I might not meet you again
僕の声が響いた
My voice echoed...
瞬間に始まる命のリミット
and at that moment, the limit of life begins
心臓がカウントしてる
My heart is counting down
叶えても叶えても終わらない願い
Wishes that never end, even if they come true
汗をかいて走った
Running and sweating,
世界の秒針はいつか止まった僕を置いていく
the world's second hand will eventually leave me behind
あと何回キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ僕を
I'm testing myself,
catch the moment
一個幸せを数えるたびに
Every time I count my happiness,
変わっていく未来に怯えてしまうけど
I get scared of the changing future,
愛情の種を大切に育てよう
but let's carefully nurture the seeds of love
分厚い雲もやがて
Thick clouds will eventually...
突き破るかな
break through, right?
キミの声が響いた
Your voice echoes,
僕の全身を通って
running through my whole body...
心臓のドアをノックしてる
to knock on the door of my heart
「臆病」でも開けちゃうんだよ
Even if I'm timid, I'll open up...
信じたいから
because I want to believe
何にもないと思った
Where I thought there was nothing...
はずの足元に
beneath my feet...
深く...
Deeply...
確かな根を生やす
we'll grow certain, strong roots.
嵐の夜が来たとしても
Even if a stormy night comes,
揺らいだりはしない
I will not waver.
何度でも 追いついたり追い越したり
Countless times, I keep chasing and surpassing you...
キミがふいに分かんなくなって
...but then, suddenly, I can't understand you anymore.
息をしたタイミングが
Just because the timing of our breaths...
合うだけで嬉しくなったりして
...matches, it makes me so happy.
集めた一秒を
The seconds I've gathered...
永遠にして
...I want to turn them into eternity.
行けるかな
I wonder if we can.
僕の声が響いた
The moment my voice resounds...
瞬間に始まる
...is when it all begins.
命のリミット
The limit of my life...
心臓がカウントしてる
...my heart is counting it down.
叶えても 叶えても
Even if they're granted, even if they come true,
終わらない願い
these wishes will never end.
汗をかいて走った
Running and dripping with sweat...
世界の秒針が
...the second hand of this world...
いつか止まった僕を置いていく
...will one day leave behind the me who has stopped.
あと何回キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ僕を Catch the moment
This world is testing me. Catch the moment!
逃さないよ僕は購入
I won't let it slip away...
この瞬間を掴め
...I'll grab hold of this moment!
Catch the moment
こんばんは！どどど！
Good evening! Dododo!
お誕生日を２回迎えることになった角巻わためです！
I'm Tsunomaki Watame, celebrating my birthday twice!
本当は6月6日がお誕生日なんですけど、ぐるぐるが多くて中断、そして延期になり...
Actually, June 6th is my birthday, but due to buffering, it was cut short and postponed...
今日！
Today,
角巻わため生誕祭2026、アニソンナイトフィーバー２、改めて開催させていただくことになりました！
Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Festival 2026: Anisong Night Fever 2 is officially back on!
迅速に動いてくださった運営さんたち、
To the staff who moved so quickly,
そしてライブを観に来てくれている皆さん、本当にありがとうございます！
and to everyone who came to watch the live show, thank you so much!
１曲目「革命デュアリズム」、２曲目「Catch the Moment」と
Seeing the first song "Kakumei Dualism" and the second "Catch the Moment,"
観ていただいて分かった方もいるかもしれないんですが、
some of you might have already realized...
前回のライブで放送した部分は、万が一のために録画を回してくださっていたので、
But the parts broadcasted during the previous live were recorded just in case,
そちらの6月6日のバキバキ生誕当日のパフォーマンスを観ていただいて、
so you'll be watching the performance from the actual birthday on June 6th.
それ以外のソロとMCは、
For the other solo parts and MC segments,
改めてこれ以上ライブが延期にならないように、今回は事前に収録をさせていただきました！
we pre-recorded them to make sure there are no more delays!
なので、未来のリアルタイムのみんなのコメントを
So, I'll be doing my MC while trying to predict...
予知しながらMCしたいなと思いますので、いっぱいコメントしてください！
...your real-time comments from the future, so please leave lots of comments!
うんうん、分かったよ、はい、はい、うん、
Uh-huh, I see. Yes, yes, mhm...
あ、ありがとうね！おめでとうもありがとう！見える、見えるぞ！
Ah, thank you! Thank you for the birthday wishes too! I can see them, I can see them!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
説明はここまで！
That's it for the explanation!
ここからはいつものライブ！
From here on, it's the usual live show!
今日は生誕ライブなので、
Since this is my birthday live,
たくさんこのライブに向けて準備や練習を、本当にたくさんしてきました！
I've put in a lot of preparation and practice—really, so much of it!
ぜひ最後まで楽しんで、そしていっぱいお祝いしてもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you enjoy it to the end and celebrate with me!
本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Today's hashtag is right here!
6月6日と変わらず、
It's the same as June 6th,
「角巻わため生誕祭2026」になりますので、たくさんスクショとか感想とかポストしてください！
it's '#角巻わため生誕祭2026', so please post lots of screenshots and thoughts!
目指せ！またトレンド、1位！
Let's aim for 1st place on trending again!
後でじっとり、ねっとり、わためも見に行いたいと思ってますので、よろしくお願いします！
I'll be checking them out thoroughly later, so please post away!
では、ここまで、
Now, so far,
dandanの「革命デュアリズム」、ソードアート・オンラインの「Catch the Moment」と歌わせていただいたんですが、
I've performed 'Kakumei Dualism' and Sword Art Online's 'Catch the Moment'...
アニメや原曲MVに関連している
...with some stage effects related to the anime and original MVs,
演出を入れ込んだりしているので、みんな分かったかな？
did you guys notice them?
ターボわためーととか、分かったかな？
Did you guys notice things like Turbo Watamate?
ぜひ細かいところまで観てもらえると嬉しいです！
I hope you look closely at all the little details!
ここからはゲストパートもあります！
From here, we have the guest performances too!
みんなの好きなアニソンも出てくるかも？
Maybe your favorite anisong will be performed?
ということで、ゲストパート、盛り上がっていきましょう！
So, let's get hyped up for the guest part!
割れた鏡の中 映る君の姿
Your reflection in the broken mirror...
泣いている 泣いている
is crying, is crying...
細い月をなぞる指
Fingers tracing the crescent moon.
誰を呼んでいるの 消えた恋の背中
Who are you calling out to? The back of a faded love...
何度でも 何度でも
Again and again, again and again,
君の窓を叩くから
Because I'll keep knocking on your window.
夜の加速度に 背中押されて
Pushed forward by the acceleration of the night,
糸が切れる様に
as if the thread is about to snap...
ただ、君を 君を強く
I was simply holding you, holding you...
抱いてた
so tightly.
アンバランスなKissを交わして
Let's share an unbalanced kiss
愛に近づけよ
and draw closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
May your tears, and your sad lies too,
僕の心に
rest...
眠れ
...in my heart.
昨日へのMerry-go-round 君を運んでゆく
The merry-go-round to yesterday carries you away.
止めたくて 止めたくて
Desperately wanting to stop it, to stop it,
僕は鍵を探してる
I am searching for the key.
崩れ落ちそうな 空を支えて
Supporting a sky that seems about to collapse,
ひとり立ち尽くす
I stand here all alone...
ただ、君の 君の側に
Simply wanting to be...
いたいよ
...by your side.
アンバランスなKissで書かれた
Written with an unbalanced kiss,
ふたりのシナリオ
is a scenario for the two of us.
愛と呼ぶほど 強くなくても
Even if it's not strong enough to be called love,
君のすべてが
everything about you...
痛い
...is painful.
ただ、君の 君の側に
Simply wanting to be...
いたいよ
...by your side.
アンバランスなKissを交わして
Let's share an unbalanced kiss
愛に近づけよ
and draw closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
May your tears, and your sad lies too,
僕の心に
rest...
眠れ
...in my heart.
君の心が僕を呼ぶまで
Until your heart calls out to me,
抱きしめあえる
until the day we can hold each other...
日まで
...tight.
長い髪なびかせて
With long, fluttering hair,
悩ましげなボディ
and a seductive body,
この都会を ハイヒールで
if I fly around this city in high heels...
飛び回れば big money coming, yeah
big money is coming, yeah!
摩天楼の足下
At the foot of the skyscrapers,
時代錯誤の罠
traps out of step with the times.
血迷った危ない奴らなら
If they're dangerous, out-of-their-mind types,
極楽へいかせちゃうわ
I'll send them straight to paradise!
大胆な
With any of my bold...
大胆な私の業の中どれでも
Among my bold techniques, whichever...
スキなのをあげる
...one you like, I will give to you.
Bye bye sadness, and find out
行き場のない
With nowhere to go...
あなた(Ghost)だから…
Because you are a Ghost...
Bye bye sadness, and find out
私が今
I am...
見つけ出して…
...finding you now...
Ghost Sweeper
吸引もいいけれど
Suction is fine, but...
神通棍はどう？
...how about the Divine Power Rod?
わがままは許さないわ
I won't allow selfishness!
逃がせないの Big money coming, yeah!
I can't let you escape, Big money coming, yeah!
コンシャスなドレスから
From a conscious dress...
ゴージャスなライフも
...to a gorgeous life...
いつだって後からついてくる
...it always follows from behind.
それが私のスタイル
That is my style.
クールだと誰かがゆうけれど
Someone says I'm cool, but...
必ず
...I will definitely...
幸せをあげる
...give you happiness.
Bye bye sadness, and find out
行き場のない
With nowhere to go...
あなた(Ghost)だから…
Because you are a Ghost...
Bye bye sadness, and find out
私が今
I am...
見つけ出して…
...finding you now...
Ghost Sweeper
Bye bye sadness, and find out
行き場のない
With nowhere to go...
あなた(Ghost)だから…
Because you are a Ghost...
Bye bye sadness, and find out
私が今
I am...
見つけ出して…
...finding you now...
Ghost Sweeper
魂の色は
What color...
何色ですか
...is your soul?
“もういっそ 折れたままで”
“It's better to just stay broken”
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
To throw it away, to run away...
強くないよ
...I'm not that strong.
ほら もう一度 鼓動高鳴る
Look, once again my heart is racing.
何が正しいかなんて
What is correct...
わからないけど
...I don't know, but...
形のないものばかりが
Only formless things...
大切になって行く
...are becoming precious.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words...
強く結ばれてる
...are strongly bound together.
また躓いて 転がって
I trip and roll over again...
それでも砕けない
...but even so, I won't break.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって
I'm just hurt and acting tough...
それでも見つけたいよ
...but even so, I want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I am verifying the shape of my soul.
深い地の底で一人
Alone at the bottom of the deep earth...
扉と鍵を探す
...I look for the door and key.
おとぎ話は ほら
Look, the fairy tale...
泡の様に全部消えて
...has disappeared completely like bubbles.
葛藤 残像だけ
Only conflicts and afterimages...
次の頁へ
...onto the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて
The growing branches and leaves part ways...
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて それぞれの道を行く
The growing branches separate and go their own ways...
寂しい思い出だけが 強く根を張ってる
Only the lonely memories have taken deep root.
また 貫いて 失って それでも挫けない
I pierce and lose again, yet I do not give up.
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Just left behind and falling out, yet I still want to convey it...
魂の日々を 魂の意志を ずっと
The days of the soul, the will of the soul, always...
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the soul?
赤い色ですか
Is it red?
青い色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
The color of the soul is...
何色ですか
What color is it?
透明な過去に 不透明な明日に
In the transparent past, in the opaque tomorrow...
生きるあなたは 何色ですか
What color are you who lives on?
また 躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
I stumble and fall again, yet I don't shatter.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the soul?
ただ 傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and acting tough, yet I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I am confirming the shape of the soul.
イェーイ！ 3曲連続でお届けしましたが、
Yay! I delivered three songs in a row,
みんな、楽しんでますかー？
is everyone having fun?!
快適に見れてますかー？
Are you able to watch comfortably?!
えー、幽☆遊☆白書の「アンバランスなKISSをして」は、月をね、映してもらったり、
We had the moon projected for Yu Yu Hakusho's 'Unbalanced Kiss,'
戦闘シーンをイメージして炎に囲まれていたり、
being surrounded by fire to evoke a combat scene,
ダンスの振りにもね、キャラクターの技が入っていたりしておりまして、
and even in the dance choreography, the characters' moves were incorporated.
「GS美神 極楽大作戦!!」の「GHOST SWEEPER」にも、お札をね、持っている振りが、あったり、
In 'GHOST SWEEPER' from GS Mikami, there was a move where I hold paper charms,
あとは幽霊が飛んでいるそんな演出があったりしました！ 気付いたかな？
and there was also an effect with flying ghosts! Did you notice?
そして、ソードアート・オンラインの「ANIMA」は、いつか歌いたいと思っていた曲で、
And Sword Art Online's 'ANIMA' is a song I've wanted to sing for a long time,
満を持しての披露だったんですが、いかがだったでしょうかー？
so it was a highly anticipated performance, but how did you like it?!
いや、かっこよかったなー！
Man, that was so cool!
すごいな、わためバキバキだな！うふふっ。
Wow, Watame was totally shredding it! (laughs)
では！ え、まだこれで終わりではありません！
Now then! This is not the end yet!
ここからは、鏡ゲートを使ったギミックや、
From here on, we'll have gimmicks using the mirror gates,
やってみたかった演出なども入ってくるので、
as well as performances I've wanted to try,
さらに盛り上がる、爆沸きステージをいっぱいやっていきたいと思います！
so I want to show you lots of super exciting, high-energy stages!
それでは！ 行ってきまーす！
Well then, here I go!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
An unrivaled smile, devastating the media
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
I want to know that secret, mysterious
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even the parts she's missing are her area
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You, perfect and a liar, are
天才的なアイドル様
the ultimate, genius-like idol!
今日何食べた？
What did you eat today?
好きな本は？
What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
If you go out to play, where do you go?
何も食べてない
I haven't eaten anything
それは内緒
That's a secret
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
No matter what you ask, dodging it so easily
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So nonchalantly, yet so brilliantly,
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
the secret that seems visible but isn't, tastes like honey
あれもないないない これもないないない
There's none of that, none of this either
好きなタイプは？ 相手は？ さあ答えて
What's your favorite type? Your partner? Come on, answer!
「誰かを好きになることなんて私わからなくてさ」
"I don't really understand what it means to fall in love with someone."
そんな言葉に
With those words,
また一人堕ちる
another person falls for them,
また好きにさせる
and you make them fall in love again.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone's eyes are being stolen by you,
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
you are the perfect and ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない
Someone like you will never appear again,
一番星の生まれ変わり
the reincarnation of the brightest star.
その笑顔で愛してるで
With that smile, with those 'I love yous,'
誰も彼も虜にしていく
you make everyone your captive.
その瞳がその言葉が
Those eyes, those words,
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
even if they're lies, that is the perfect love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, yes, that girl is special,
我々はハナからおまけです
we were just extras from the start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're just the supporting cast B for the star,
全てがアノ子の御陰なわけない
it's impossible that everything is thanks to her.
洒落臭い
It's annoying!
妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
How can there not be any jealousy or envy?
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
This isn't a joke, which is why I can't forgive it.
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない自分を許せない
I can't forgive you for not being perfect, I can't forgive myself.
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't acknowledge anyone but you, who is stronger than anyone else.
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone believes in you and worships you,
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
you are truly the strongest and invincible idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
There are no weaknesses to be found,
一番星を宿している
you carry the brightest star within you.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
You mustn't show your weak spots,
知りたくない とこは見せずに
without showing the parts that people don't want to see.
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
You have to be one of a kind, no, no,
それこそ本物のアイ
that is the true love.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
With your signature smile, you excite the media,
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
this is the only secret you keep hidden.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
You build your career on the lie of 'I love you,'
これこそ私なりの愛だ
this is my own kind of love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even the sweat that flows is beautiful aqua,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
those eyelids that hid the ruby.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
I, who sing and dance, am Maria,
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
yes, lies are the most special kind of love.
誰かに愛されたことも
Whether being loved by someone...
誰かのこと愛したこともない
...or falling in love with someone, I haven't done either.
そんな私の嘘が
I believe that my lies...
いつか本当になること 信じてる
...will one day become the truth.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
Someday, I will surely get everything,
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I am such a greedy idol.
等身大でみんなのこと
Because I want to love everyone...
ちゃんと愛したいから
...with my own body.
今日も嘘をつくの
I will continue to tell lies today too,
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って保存する
wishing for the day when these words become the truth.
それでもまだ
Even so, I still...
君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
...haven't been able to say it to you and to you,
やっと言えた保存する
but I finally said it.
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is absolutely not a lie,
愛してる
I love you.
あいうえお菓子した
A-I-U-E-O- sweets under,
かきくけこんなにも保存する
Ka-Ki-Ku-Ke, still so happy.
さしすせソフトクリーム
Sa-Shi-Su-Se, soft cream,
五臓六腑でいこう
let's go with everything!
たちつてトルテ切った
Ta-Chi-Tsu-Te, torte cut,
なにぬねのり塩
Na-Ni-Nu-Ne, nori salt.
はひふへホットパイと
Ha-Hi-Fu-He, hot pie and...
みんなでぬくぬく
...everyone, nice and warm!
ショートケーキフワリ
Shortcake, fluffy,
キャンディーペロペロ
candy, licking.
チョコレートの川で
In the chocolate river,
わたがし雲見た
I saw cotton candy clouds.
アイスクリームと
With ice cream...
プリンのお城で
...and pudding castle,
カスタード渡狸
with custard Wataruki,
二人のランデブー
the two of us, a rendezvous.
パフェ色サンデー
Parfait-colored sundae,
あんこもハッピー
sweet bean paste is happy,
たい焼きにクリーム
cream on taiyaki,
小悪魔ドロップ保存する
little devil drops.
カップケーキから
From cupcake...
イチゴあんみつまで
...to strawberry anmitsu,
国境なきスイーツ
sweets without borders,
仲良くなれるよ
we can get along well.
ぼんやり夢見てごらん
Try dreaming blankly,
キャラメルみたいにくっつこう
let's stick together like caramel.
まみむめモンブラン
Ma-Mi-Mu-Me, Mont Blanc,
やいゆえヨーグルトと
Ya-I-Yu-E, yogurt and,
らりるれロールケーキ
Ra-Ri-Ru-Re, roll cake,
渡狸とキッスを
and a kiss with Wataruki.
あいうえお菓子した
A-I-U-E-O- sweets under,
かきくけこんなにも
Ka-Ki-Ku-Ke, still so happy,
さしすせソフトクリーム
Sa-Shi-Su-Se, soft cream,
五臓六腑でいこう
let's go with everything.
のんびり早弁
Leisurely early lunch,
焼きのり炙って
toast the grilled seaweed,
おにぎりコロコロ
onigiri rolling along,
友達ほかほか
friends nice and warm.
もみじまんじゅうと
Maple leaf manju and...
あんぱんお月さま
...the moon like a bean bun,
渡狸に始まり保存する
starting with Wataruki,
渡狸に終わる日々
days ending with Wataruki.
ほんのり見つめてごらん
Try looking at me slightly,
甘くて苦い夕焼けを
at the sweet and bitter sunset.
たちつてトルテ切った
Ta-Chi-Tsu-Te, torte cut,
なにぬねのり塩
Na-Ni-Nu-Ne, nori salt,
はひふへホットパイと
Ha-Hi-Fu-He, hot pie and,
みんなでぬくぬく
everyone, nice and warm.
まみむめモンブラン
Ma-Mi-Mu-Me, Mont Blanc,
やいゆえヨーグルトと
Ya-I-Yu-E, yogurt and,
らりるれロールケーキ
Ra-Ri-Ru-Re, roll cake.
ラリルーレロールケーキ 渡狸とkissを
Having a kiss with a roll cake Watanuki
ミルフィーユワッフルボンボン
Mille-feuille, waffle, bon-bon
ムース渡狸パイ
Mousse, Watanuki, pie
シュークリームバナナゼリー
Cream puffs, banana jelly
ババロア渡狸
Bavarois, Watanuki
ホットケーキバウムクーヘン
Pancakes, baumkuchen
渡狸ワタヌキ
Watanuki, Watanuki
バター渡狸クレープ
Butter crepe Watanuki
ワタヌキ渡狸
Watanuki, Watanuki
ワタヌキとごはん
Meals with Watanuki
ワタヌキとおやつ
Snacks with Watanuki
ワタヌキと肉まん
Meat buns with Watanuki
ワタヌキと北京ダック
Peking duck with Watanuki
みつまめ渡狸
Mitsumame Watanuki
渡狸シロップ
Watanuki syrup
金時ワタヌキ
Kintoki Watanuki
大盛り渡狸丼
Extra Watanuki rice bowl
こんがり思い出色
Well-done to the color of memories
ハチミツみたいにとろける...
Melting like honey
愛、上、お菓子、下
Love, up, sweets, down
柿食うっけ？ こんなにも
Wanna eat a persimmon? There's plenty to go around
差しすせソフトクリーム
Let's say that soft serve ice cream
五臓六腑でいこう
looks like innards
タッチついてトルテ来た
After giving a touch, I came to get a torte
何？ ヌネのり塩
What? With salt on top
はっ！ ヒフヘホットパイと
Oh! Hot pie with...
みんなでぬくぬく
everyone as we snuggle
まみむめモンブラン
Mont Blanc
やい！ 故ヨーグルト保存
yay! Aged yogurt
ラリルーレロールケーキ
Having a kiss with a roll cake
渡狸とkissを
Watanuki
ワタヌキの甘みと
With Watanuki's sweetness,
ワタヌキの苦み
Watanuki's bitterness,
ワタヌキの酸味で保存
And Watanuki's sourness,
好き好きラブ・コンボ
I love him, I love him, we make a love combo!
ようこそジャパリパークへ！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is also a chaotic, noisy day.
うー！がぉー！
Grrr! Roar!
高らかに笑い笑えばフレンズ
If we laugh out loud, we're friends.
喧嘩して
Even if we fight
すっちゃかめっちゃかしても仲良し保存
and things get chaotic, we're still friends.
けものは居ても のけものは居ない
Even if there are animals, there are no pariahs.
本当の愛はここにある
The true love is right here.
ほら君も手をつないで大冒険
Look, you should hold hands and go on a great adventure too!
ワン・ツー・スリー
One, Two, Three
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is also a chaotic, noisy day.
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Because everyone has their own different appearance and shape, we are attracted to each other.
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
If I gently overlap my fingers against the sunset sky,
はじめまして
Nice to meet you.
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you.
うー！がぉー！保存
Grrr! Roar!
振り向けば
If I look back,
あちらこちらでトラブル
there's trouble everywhere.
なんてこった てんでんバラバラ ちんぷんかんぷん
What the heck? Everything's scattered, it doesn't make sense...
まとまんない
...it just won't settle down.
けものですもの大目に見ててね
We're animals, so please forgive us.
みんな自由に生きている保存
Everyone is living freely.
そう君も飾らなくて大丈夫
Yes, you don't have to keep up appearances, it's okay.
はいどーぞ
Here you go
Nice to meet you ジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you Japari Park!
今日からはどうぞよろしくね
From today, please be kind to me.
いつもいつでも優しい笑顔
We were always waiting for your gentle smile,
君を待っていたの保存
anytime, anywhere.
開かれた扉 夢をいっぱい語ったら
If we talk a lot about our dreams in front of the open gate,
どこまでも続いてくグレートジャーニー保存
Great journey continuing anywhere.
うー！
Ooh!
東へ吠えろ
Roar to the East
西へ吠えろ
Roar to the West
世界中に響け
Let it echo throughout the world,
サファリメロディ保存
the Safari Melody.
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is also a chaotic, noisy day.
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Because everyone has their own different appearance and shape, we are attracted to each other.
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
If I gently overlap my fingers against the sunset sky,
はじめまして
Nice to meet you.
君をもっと知りたいな保存
I want to know more about you.
うー！がぉー！保存
Grrr! Roar!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la
Oh, welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ラララ ラララ 集まれ友達保存
La la la la, la la la, la la la, gather round, friends!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, get me once and right
Love the danger, love to break a stranger
Rocket! Rocket! Rocket! Knock to my door, I'll open
Speak my name now, speak it if you know how to
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire!
Night of fire! You better, better stay
You better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire! Come on, come over me
Come on over the top, you've never been here
You'll have a night of fire!
Night of fire!
Whoa oh, whoa oh!
You'll have a night of fire!
ということで！ここまで、たくさんの...
So, up until here, with so many...
綺麗な勝ち方は 望むべくもない
A clean victory is not something to even hope for
華やかさも必要ない それが私だから
No need for showiness either, because that's who I am
歴史はいつだって 勝者が作るモノ
History is always something made by the winners
だけど記憶はその限りじゃない
But memory is not limited to that
今この時だけは
Right now, at least for this moment...
決断的な刹那性に飛び込んでいけ
Jump into this decisive ephemeral nature!
灰色の手で描く
My thoughts drawn with gray hands...
“私” の思いが
My thoughts...
美しき痛みをも乗り越えて書き換えていく
Overcoming and rewriting even the beautiful pain!
後悔は１ミリもない
There's not a single millimeter of regret!
あるのは灼熱だけ
All there is is a burning passion!
ただ自分の生命を蹴り上げるように
Just like kicking up my own life!
始まりは些細 最早どうだっていい
The beginning was trivial, it doesn't matter anymore
突き動かされ指先を伸ばす
Driven to stretch out my fingertips!
現実は残酷だと気付いていないわけじゃない
It's not that I don't realize reality is cruel
諦めるその時は 今ではなかったらしい
It seems the time to give up wasn't 'now'!
灰色の空 赤く もう一度 点火して
Igniting the gray sky red once more!
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
Just to prove my own life!
そこにいた事を刻むように
As if carving the fact that I was there!
はい！ということで、新曲！
Yes! And with that, my new song...
『灰色の証明』！
'Proof of Gray'!
やっと披露できた！
I was finally able to perform it!
やっと証明できた！
I was finally able to prove it!
聴いてくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for listening!
この楽曲は、岸田教団&THE明星ロケッツの皆さんにご制作いただきまして
This song was created by Kishida Kyoudan & THE Akeboshi Rockets,
スポーツだったり、みんなが頑張りたい時に力になれるような応援ソングを作りたいと思い
with the hope of creating a cheering song that could give people strength when doing sports or working hard.
色々語ったら、かなり熱くてかっこいい楽曲に仕上がりました！
After discussing many things, it turned into a really passionate and cool song!
上手くいかないことがあっても、また立ち上がって前に進む
Even when things don't go well, rising up again and moving forward...
わためにとっても背中を押してくれる、そんな特別な楽曲に今回のライブでなりました！
today's live concert made this a very special song that pushes Watame forward!
みんなにとってもそうだったら嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if it is the same for all of you!
こちらの新曲MV、いっぱい見て、楽曲もぜひ購入して
Please watch the MV for this new song a lot, and purchase the track too,
わための音楽を応援していただけたらとっても嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you could support Watame's music!
目指せ、サードライブ！
Aiming for the 3rd Live!
あ、ここで、まだ告知していないものが1つありまして。ライブじゃないんですけど、なんと！
Ah, and here is one more thing I haven't announced yet. It's not a live concert, but...
どじゃーん！
Ta-da!
『角巻わための Have a nice day』が書籍刊行決定！
The publication of the book 'Tsunomaki Watame's Have a Nice Day' has been confirmed!
ということで、ハバナが本になります！
So, 'Habana' is becoming a book!
出版社は『かいけつゾロリ』や『おしりたんてい』などで有名なポプラ社様より
It will be published by Poplar Publishing, famous for 'Kaiketsu Zorori' and 'Oshiri Tantei',
オリジナルグッズ付きで12月に刊行予定です！
and is scheduled for release in December with original merchandise!
まだ少し先にはなりますが、楽しみに待ってもらえると嬉しいです！
It's still a bit of a way off, but I'd be happy if you look forward to it!
そして！どどーん！
And! Ta-da!
今年も、角巻わため誕生日記念グッズが受注受付中です！
Pre-orders for Tsunomaki Watame's birthday commemorative merchandise are open this year too!
ラインナップを改めて紹介させてくださーい！
Let me introduce the lineup to you once again!
ど、ど、ど、ど、どん！
Do, do, do, do, don!
じゃじゃーん！ふーみママ描き下ろしの、わためのあったかブランケット！
Ta-da! Watame's Warm Blanket, illustrated by Fuumi-mama!
なんと、セクシーです！
It's actually quite sexy!
そして、裏面にはわためいとがいます！
And on the back, there are Watamates!
丸めるとね、わためいとの形になりますので、2wayでも使えます。ぜひ温もりを感じてください！
If you roll it up, it takes the shape of a Watamate, so it can be used in two ways. Please feel the warmth!
そして、どどどどどん！
And, do-do-do-do-don!
わため&わためいと温感マグカップ！
The Watame & Watamate Thermal Mug!
こちらは、もた先生に描き下ろしていただきまして
This one was illustrated by Mota-sensei.
最初は夜の風景なんですけど、温かいものを入れていただくとその熱を感知して
At first it shows a night scene, but when you pour a hot drink inside, it senses the heat...
朝の景色に柄が変わるような仕様になっております！
and the design changes to a morning scene!
わための配信を意識してデザインしてもらったので
I had them design it with Watame's streams in mind,
配信を見ながらぜひ温かい飲み物を飲んでくださいね！
so please enjoy a hot drink while watching my streams!
そして、まだあります！
And there's still more!
どどどどどどどどん！
Do-do-do-do-do-do-do-don!
わためいとクッション！,s:
The Watamate Cushion!
クッションとして使うもよし、飾るもよし
You can use it as a cushion, or display it as a decoration.
とっても可愛いクッションなので、ぜひお部屋に...
It's a very cute cushion, so please add it to your room...
...に置いてみてください！
...please try placing it there!
最後に、ドドドドドドドドドドドドン！
Lastly... *drumroll*... dun!
じゃーん！わためなりきりアイマスク！
Ta-da! The Watame Cosplay Eye Mask!
眠っている顔と、わためと言えばこれ！な表情にしていただきました。
It features a sleeping face, and of course, this expression which is classic Watame!
果たして需要あるのか！？気になる方はぜひなりきりアイマスク手に入れてください！
Is there actually a demand for this?! If you're curious, please do get the cosplay eye mask!
こちらのグッズをフルセットで購入していただいた方には...
And for those who purchase these goods as a full set...
ドルルルル... ドン！
*drumroll*... Dun!
わための直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと、つのまきわためのショートボイスセット15種類が特典としてついてきます！
A postcard with my handwritten signature and a message, plus a set of 15 short voice clips will be included as a bonus!
今年も無制限で直筆を書かせていただく予定なので、ぜひこの機会にゲットしてみてください！
I'm planning to do unlimited handwritten signatures again this year, so please take this opportunity to get them!
ということで、新曲MV公開中！楽曲リリース中！
And so, the new song's MV is out now! The digital track is released!
誕生日グッズ発売中！12月、初の書籍刊行決定！
Birthday goods are on sale! And in December, my very first book release is confirmed!
よろしくお願いいたします！この後は10時15分からメン限アンコールライブもありますので、よかったらメンバーに入っていただいて、引き続き楽しみましょう！
Please look forward to it! After this, starting at 10:15 PM, we'll have a member-only encore live show, so please join the membership and let's keep having fun together!
今年はなんと2Days！お誕生日たくさんお祝いしてくれて、ありがとう！
It's a 2-day event this year! Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday with me!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです！それでは、メン限アンコールライブで会いましょう！まったねー！
I was incredibly happy! Well then, see you at the member-only encore live show! Bye-bye!
この手伸ばして
Reaching out my hand
掴み取る未来
to grasp the future,
どんなに遠くても
no matter how far it is,
走り続けるよ
I will keep on running.
いつだって一人じゃない
We are never alone,
みんながいるから
because everyone is here.
信じる道を
Along the path we believe in,
進んでいこう
let's move forward.
手と手を取り合って
Holding hands together,
笑顔を咲かせよう
let's make smiles bloom,
未来へ続く
continuing into the future,
キセキを描いて
painting a miracle.
響け私たちの声
Let our voices resound,
空を越えて
crossing over the sky,
届けたいんだ
because we want to deliver it
君の元へ
to where you are.
ずっとずっと
Forever and ever,
この場所で
in this place,
歌い続けるよ
we will keep on singing,
ありがとうを込めて
filled with our gratitude.
これからも夢に向かって一緒に歩いて行こうね！
Let's keep walking together toward our dreams!!